Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Weird” is from the Old English “wyrd” meaning _.",
  answer: "destiny",
  explanation: "The word was used to mean “uncanny” or “supernatural” in Middle English, which Shakespeare’s “Macbeth” took to mean “odd-looking.”"
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Flower” is from the Old French “flour” which itself comes from the Latin word _.",
  answer: "flos",
  explanation: "“Flower” was originally a variant of “flour” (literally meaning “blossom”, figuratively meaning “the best part”), and became used to refer to ground grain in the 17th century."
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Victory” is from the Anglo-Norman French “victorie” which itself comes from the Latin word _.",
  answer: "victoria",
  explanation: "“Victoria” in Latin is a first declension of the Latin “victor,” or conqueror."
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "The word “Mortgage” developed in late Middle English, but is from the same Old French word literally meaning _.",
  answer: "dead pledge",
  explanation: "The Old French word derives from the Latin “mortuus” (dead), becoming Old French “mort,” and the Old French “gage” meaning pledge. Maybe I’ll rent for a few more years."
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Robot” is from the Czech “robota” meaning _.",
  answer: "forced labor",
  explanation: "The term was coined in 1920 in K. Čapek’s play R.U.R. (Rossum’s Universal Robots, or, originally, Rossumovi Univerzální Roboti)."
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Nimrod” which now means a silly fool comes from the Hebrew “nimrōḏ” originally meaning _.",
  answer: "skillful hunter",
  explanation: "The word comes from Nimrod who is the great-grandson of Noah in Genesis 10:8-9. It was used literally, then ironically… and then somehow we redefined it. English is weird."
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Whiskey” comes from the Scottish Gaelic “uisge beatha,” literally meaning _.",
  answer: "water of life",
  explanation: "“Uisge beatha” became “usquebaugh,” which became “whiskeybae” which was shortened to “whiskey.” Bae please."
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Hazard” is from the Persian and Turkish “zar” meaning _.",
  answer: "dice",
  explanation: "It became “az-zahr” in Arabic, meaning chance or luck; then Spanish “azar” to Old French “hasard” before landing in Middle English as “hazard.”"
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Quarantine” comes from the Italian “quaranta” meaning _.",
  answer: "forty",
  explanation: "Ships arriving at Venetian ports from plague-ridden countries were held for 40 days to prevent the spread of the plague. The Italian word is based in the Latin “quadraginta,” but not with the same meaning."
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Muscle” is from the Latin “mus” meaning _.",
  answer: "mouse",
  explanation: "They’re like a mouse under the rug, if the rug was your skin. Has anyone actually seen a mouse under the rug?"
)
Question.find_or_create_by(
  prompt: "“Curfew” comes from the Old French “cuevrefeu,” literally meaning _.",
  answer: "cover fire",
  explanation: "It was used in reference to a regulation requiring fires to be extinguished at a certain time in the evening."
)
